（鳥のさえずり）
Tendo Martial Arts Sword Drawing
First Style, Number 1:
（天童(てんどう)木更(きさら)）
天童式抜刀術 一の型一番
Tekisui Seihyo!
滴水成氷(てきすいせいひょう)
She's unbelievably fast
with a sword, as always...
（里見(さとみ)蓮太郎(れんたろう)）相変わらず
とんでもねえ剣速だな
Not to mention that's Yukikage,
a sword meant to kill.
しかも 殺人刀(せつにんとう)･雪影(ゆきかげ)…
Rentaro! How long are you
going to keep me waiting?
（藍原(あいはら)延珠(えんじゅ)）蓮太郎！
いつまで待たせるのだ！
Listen.
（蓮太郎）
いいか ゴム弾といっても―
Just because they're rubber bullets,
it doesn't mean they won't hurt.
当たったら
痛いじゃ済まないんだからな
I'm aware of that!
（延珠）分かってる！
（銃声）
（延珠）てやっ
ていっ
フッフーン
あ…
How was my fighting?
妾(わらわ)の戦いぶりは どうだった？
Try not to high kick while wearing a skirt.
スカートでハイキックすんのは
やめとけ
うわっ　うっ
You know you liked it.
うれしいくせに
♪～
～♪
#05 The Crimson Black Assassin
You still haven't found a
new school for Enju-chan?
（木更）延珠ちゃんの
新しい学校―
まだ 見つからないの？
Nope...
（蓮太郎）ああ
Why not have her go to a
school in the Outer District?
（木更）この際 外周区の学校に
通わせたらどう？
You mean that open-air classroom
surrounded by abandoned buildings?
あの廃虚ばかりの青空教室にか？
What's important is finding a place where
優先すべきは
延珠ちゃんにとって
Enju-chan feels comfortable, isn't it?
居心地がいいかどうかでしょ？
Well, I'll consider it...
まあ 考えておくよ
Regardless, you'll need money, right?
なんにしても
先立つものは必要よね
あっ
We've got a job. It's a bodyguard request.
（木更）依頼がきてるの
内容は護衛任務
Bodyguard? For who?
護衛？ 誰の？
Believe it or not, you've been
hand-picked by Seitenshi-sama herself,
なんと 聖天子(せいてんし)様
じきじきのご指名よ
Satomi-kun.
里見くん
（聖天子）あ…
Good day, Satomi-san.
ごきげんよう 里見さん
The day after tomorrow,
（聖天子）明後日
大阪エリア代表の斉武(さいたけ)大統領が―
President Saitake,
who represents the Osaka Area,
will be visiting the Tokyo
Area for an informal meeting.
非公式に 東京エリアを訪れます
Saitake Sogen? For what?
（蓮太郎）
斉武宗玄(そうげん)が？ なんのために？
I do not know.
分かりません
But I believe his biggest reason
ただ 今である理由は
for choosing this moment
was Kikunojo-san's absence.
菊之丞(きくのじょう)さんの不在が大きいかと
That's right, the geezer's in China
or Russia or something now, isn't he?
（蓮太郎）
そういや あのじじいは―
中国だかロシアだかに
行ってるんだっけか？
I would like for you to be next
to me when we are traveling,
里見さんには
移動中は 私(わたくし)の隣に
and behind me when I am
in meetings, and guard me.
会談中は 私の後ろに控えて
警護してほしいのです
You already have bodyguards, don't you?
護衛ならいるだろ？
Indeed. Let me introduce them to you.
（聖天子）
ええ 紹介いたしましょう
I am the head of the bodyguards,
Second Lieutenant Yasuwaki Takuto.
（保脇(やすわき)卓人(たくと)）
護衛隊長の保脇卓人３尉です
We'll be counting on you if
anything should happen,
もしものときは
よろしくお願いしますよ
Satomi-kun.
里見くん
I only came here today to get an explanation.
今日は 説明を受けに来ただけだ
I haven't agreed to take the job yet.
まだ 依頼を受けると
決めたわけじゃねえよ
I will look forward to a positive response.
よい返事をお待ちしてます
Don't expect too much.
（蓮太郎）あんまり期待すんなよ
フゥ…
I'm lost.
迷った…
Damn it. This place is too big.
ったく 広すぎるんだよ ここ
（撃鉄を起こす音）
（護衛官）ううっ
（蓮太郎）ぐっ…
What are you playing at?
なんのマネだ？
Satomi Rentaro, refuse this job.
里見蓮太郎
この依頼を断れ
What?
（蓮太郎）ああ？
Lord Tendo left Seitenshi-sama
in my hands before he left.
天童閣下は この僕に
聖天子様を託して発たれた
The spot next to Seitenshi-sama
belongs to me.
聖天子様の隣は 僕のものだ
I'm not taking orders from you.
（蓮太郎）
あんたの指図は受けねえよ
Shatter the bones in his arms and legs.
腕と足の骨を粉砕しろ
（護衛官）うおっ
（銃声）
Bastard...
貴様…
What's that noise?!
（職員）なんの音だ？
It came from over there!
（職員）向こうからだ！
（保脇）くっ… 行くぞ！
Let's go.
I'm going to kill you...
殺してやる…
I'm going to kill you, Satomi Rentaro!
殺してやるぞ！ 里見蓮太郎！
（遠ざかる足音）
（走る足音）
What happened here?
I thought I heard gun shots.
（警備員）どうされました？
銃声がしたようですが…
Please tell Seitenshi
聖天子に伝えてくれ
that I'll be taking the job.
依頼 受けるってな
（男性）イッテーな こらっ！
That hurt, damn it!
You run over someone's foot with
a bike and have nothing to say?
チャリで 人の足 踏んどいて―
挨拶もなしか？ ああ？
Man, it's totally broken.
（男性）あーあ こりゃ折れてるな
You're gonna have to pay the bill for that.
（男性）慰謝料だ 慰謝料
Yeah!
（男性）そうだ そうだ
（蓮太郎）ハァ…
You're not worth talking to.
Go call your parents.
（男性）てめえじゃ 話にならねえ
とりあえず 親 呼べや
ああ？
Who the hell are you?
なんだ？ てめえは
（一同）うっ…
Hey, let's go.
おい 行くぞ！
R-Right...
（男性たち）お… おう！
ハァ…
ん？
I've never seen a superhero before...
（ティナ）正義のヒーロー
生まれて初めて見ました
Um... Where am I?
あの… ここ どこですか？
There. All clean.
（蓮太郎）よしっ キレイになった
Thank you very... mu...
ありがとうございます…
Hey.
おい！
Caffeine?
（蓮太郎）カフェイン？
I'm nocturnal, so this is the only way
I can stay awake during the day.
私 夜型なので
こうしていないと
昼は起きていられないんです
What's your name?
（蓮太郎）お前 名前は？
Where'd you come from?
Where's your guardian?
どこから来たんだ？ 保護者は？
And what are you doing out
here in pajamas and slippers?
だいたい なんで
パジャマとスリッパなんだ？
I'm not sure.
さあ？
You're not sure? Then what about your name?
（蓮太郎）さあって…
じゃあ 名前
It's...
それは…
Tina.
ティナです
Tina Sprout.
ティナ･スプラウト
I'm Satomi Rentaro.
俺は 里見蓮太郎だ
All right, Tina, I'm asking you again.
いいか ティナ
もう一度 聞く
Where's your guardian?
保護者は どうした？
I don't have one.
（ティナ）いません
Then where'd you come from?
（蓮太郎）
だったら どこから来た？
I believe, today, I woke up in my apartment,
確か 今日は
アパートで目が覚めて
brushed my teeth, took a shower,
歯を磨いて シャワーを浴びて
changed my clothes, and then quickly...
服を着替えて さっそうと…
Don't lie! You haven't changed,
and you haven't taken a shower.
ウソつくんじゃねえよ！
服も着替えてないし
シャワーも浴びてない
It's obvious you just woke up.
どう見たって 寝起きだろ
Wow... You know me better
than I know myself.
ほーう 私より
私のことをご存じなのですね
（蓮太郎）フゥ…
Forget it. Just go to a police box.
もういい お前 交番に行け
I can't really do that...
それは ちょっと…
I've realized that you're
more than I can handle.
（蓮太郎）お前の相手は
俺には無理だと分かった
You can call me if something happens,
何かあったら電話していいから
交番行け　頼むから
but just go to the police box. Please.
（携帯電話の操作音）
Why are you calling me right now?
なぜ 今 かける？
You might have given me a fake
phone number, Rentaro-san.
蓮太郎さんが 偽の電話番号を
教えたかもしれません
（携帯電話の着信音）
Hello?
もしもし
I failed to mention this,
but I know where my apartment is.
言いそびれましたが 私
自分のアパートの場所 分かります
What?
なに…
Today was a very fun day.
今日は とても楽しい１日でした
I hope we'll see each other again.
また 会えるといいですね
Well then, goodbye, Rentaro-san.
では さようなら 蓮太郎さん
What the hell was up with her?
なんだったんだ？ あいつは
（携帯電話の着信音）
I have successfully
infiltrated the Tokyo Area.
東京エリアへの潜入に
成功しました
On my way to retrieve the item.
アイテムの回収に向かいます
Tina Sprout, let me confirm.
（マスター）ティナ･スプラウト
いま一度 確認する
Tell me, what is your mission?
お前の任務は何か
私に聞かせておくれ
The assassination of the
Tokyo Area representative,
（ティナ）東京エリアの代表
聖天子の抹殺です
Seitenshi, Master.
マスター
Rental Box
Little girl, where'd you come from?
（警官）
お嬢ちゃん どこの子だい？
You shouldn't be out here this late.
Where's your house?
ダメだよ こんな時間に出歩いちゃ
おうち どこ？
Master, this is an unforeseen incident.
マスター 不測の事態です
A police officer is talking to me.
警官に声をかけられました
Kill him.
（マスター）殺せ
Hm?
（警官）ん？
This is pretty bad...
ひでえな こりゃ…
Did the Cursed Children go on a rampage again?
（男性）また 呪われた子供たちが
暴れたのか！
The police officer who was attacked
（男性）襲われた警官は
意識不明の重体らしいぞ
is apparently unconscious
and in critical condition.
Why can't everyone just get along?
どうして みんな
仲良くできないのかな
I don't know.
（蓮太郎）分からん
All right. Let's go home.
よし 帰るぞ
（延珠）うん
Okay, it should be ready now.
（蓮太郎）さあ そろそろいいぞ
Let's ea—
いただきま…
（チャイム）
Who the hell is it at this hour?
誰だよ こんな時間に
Satomi-chan!
（司馬(しば)未織(みおり)）里見ちゃーん
M-Miori?! What are you doing here?
未織!? 何しに来たんだよ
（未織のせき込み）
Take care of me...
（未織）看病して…
Rentaro, who is this woman?
蓮太郎 この女は何者だ？
This is Shiba Miori.
こいつは 司馬未織
She's the student council
president at Magata High School
勾田(まがた)高校の生徒会長にして
and daughter of the president of the large-scale
weapons company, Shiba Heavy Weapons.
巨大兵器会社 司馬重工の
社長令嬢だよ
（足音）
S-Satomi-kun...
さ… 里見くん
Kisara-san?!
木更さん！
M-Make sukiyaki with this...
（木更）こ…これで
すき焼き作って
I'm... hungry...
（木更）おなか すいた…
（未織）ぎゅむっ
Please, Enju...
（蓮太郎）頼む 延珠
Dispose of one of them.
どっちか片方 捨ててきてくれ
What are you talking about?
む？ 何を言ってるのだ？
These two hate each other so much,
（蓮太郎）この２人は
死ぬほど仲が悪くて―
putting them together causes
some horrific chemical reaction.
一緒にすると すさまじい
化学反応を起こすんだよ
I thought you had a cold.
お前 かぜじゃなかったのかよ
Actually,
それが
it seems the cold medicine and
energy drink worked wonders.
かぜ薬とドリンク剤が
劇的に効いたみたいなんよ
And then I got hungry suddenly.
そしたら 急に
おなかが減ってきてな
Sorry to have you feed me.
ごちそうになってもうて 悪いなあ
Indeed, you should be.
ええ 悪いわね
I'd prefer it if a snake like you,
who didn't bring any ingredients
具材も持ってこずに
タダ飯にありついてるような
ヘビ女には
and got to eat for free,
would leave immediately.
すぐに出ていってほしいわ
Oh, you're here, Kisara?
あら おったん？ 木更
Your boobs are so big,
I couldn't see your face.
胸がでかくて
顔が よぉ見えんかったわ
（木更）うっ
By the way, Satomi-kun,
ところで 里見くん
I sent off the paperwork.
書類のほう 出しておいたわよ
Got it. Thanks.
（蓮太郎）分かった ありがとう
They want you to start tomorrow,
so the rest is on you.
明日から
お願いしたいってことだから
よろしくね
We have work, Rentaro?
仕事か？ 蓮太郎
Yeah. Bodyguard duty this time.
（蓮太郎）
ああ 今度は護衛任務だ
よろしくな
I'm counting on you.
All right!
よーし きたのだー！
So you must be Enju-chan.
あなたが 延珠ちゃんね
How do you like the feel of those shoes?
靴の履き心地はどうえ？
Huh?
Those are shoes my company
designed for fighting.
（延珠）えっ？
（未織）あの靴はな―
戦闘用に
うちがデザインしたやつなんよ
I see!
そうだったのか！
Also, the Varanium bullets that
Satomi-chan fires off everywhere
（未織）あとな
里見ちゃんが ばらまいてる―
バラニウム弾も―
are provided by my company, too.
みーんな うちの会社が
提供しとるんよ
But Rentaro can't afford to pay for all that.
（延珠）でも 蓮太郎は
そんなお金 払えないであろう
It's free.
It's free?!
（未織）タダや
（延珠）タダなのか!?
When we civil officers use a weapon,
俺たち民警が 武器を使うことで
we're promoting the company that made it.
それを作った会社の
宣伝になるからな
The moment I laid eyes on
Satomi-chan, it struck me.
うちは 里見ちゃんを見た瞬間
ビビッときたんよ
I knew he would make it big someday.
これは 将来 大物になるってな
So we gave him the okay,
with some conditions.
だから 条件付きで
オーケーしたんよ
What do you mean by conditions?
（延珠）条件とは なんなのだ？
There are a few.
いろいろあるで
One of them was that he would study
at Magata High School with me.
うちと同じ勾田高校で
一緒にお勉強しましょってのも
その１つや　フフッ
Satomi-chan belongs to only me.
里見ちゃんは うちだけのものや
（木更）うっ
H-Hey, get off of me.
お… おい 離れろって
Say, Satomi-chan, why don't
you quit Kisara's company
なあ 里見ちゃん
木更のとこなんかやめて
and come work for our civil security unit?
うちの民警部門で働かん？
Say, Satomi-kun,
ねえ 里見くん
this is delicious and all,
この鍋 おいしいけど
何か足りないと思わない？
but don't you think something's missing?
Huh?
It's...
（蓮太郎）えっ？
（木更）それはね…
Miori's blood.
未織の血よ
You're not going to back down, are you?
（未織）引く気はないようやな
There we go.
（延珠･蓮太郎）よいしょっと…
I'll send you to hell.
あの世に送ったげる！
I'll make you grovel before my Shiba Style!
司馬流の前に
ひれ伏せさせたるわ！
（激突音）
So much for getting my
security deposit back...
（蓮太郎）敷金 返ってこないな…
Rentaro, do your best at work!
（延珠）蓮太郎
お仕事 頑張ってくるのだ！
Satomi-san, you've met President
Saitake previously, right?
里見さん
あなたは 斉武大統領と
面識があるのですよね？
When I was taken in at the Tendo mansion,
天童の屋敷に
引き取られていたころ
the geezer dragged me around everywhere,
クソじじいに連れ回されて
including to all kinds of parties.
いろんなパーティーにも
出てたからな
How would you describe President Saitake?
あなたから見た斉武大統領は
どのような人なのですか？
A dictator.
独裁者
あ… 冗談ですか？
Surely you jest...
I'm serious. Sapporo, Sendai, Hakata...
（蓮太郎）マジだよ
札幌 仙台 博多
All the Area heads are the same.
どこのトップもそうだが―
They all restored their
Areas within a generation
ヤツらは ガストレア大戦後の
荒廃期から―
from the age of devastation
after the Gastrea War.
たった一代で
エリアを立て直した―
They're all extremely efficient,
yet dangerous guys.
とびきり有能で
そして危険な連中だ
And among them all,
Saitake is the most dangerous.
中でも 斉武は一番ヤバい
気をつけろ
Be careful.
I thank you for the warning.
ご忠告 ありがたく
受け取っておきます
Satomi-san, please do not leave my side.
里見さん 私のそばを
離れないでくださいね
It's a pleasure to meet you, Seitenshi-sama.
（斉武宗玄）
はじめまして 聖天子様
Is this boy next to you
the brat Tendo adopted?
隣にいるのは
天童のもらわれっ子か
You're still alive, huh?
てめえこそ まだ生きてたのか
Watch your mouth. You're only a civil officer.
フンッ
口を慎め 民警風情が
Please take a seat, Seitenshi-sama.
まずは お座りください
聖天子様
Rentaro, I heard that you
destroyed the rail gun module.
蓮太郎 貴様
レールガンモジュールを
破壊したそうだな
What if I did?
だったら なんだってんだ？
That weapon was to be
transferred to the moon's surface,
あれは いずれ月面に移設し
and eventually used to target
and destroy the Gastrea on Earth.
月から 地球のガストレアを
狙い撃つ兵器だったのだ
And yet you...
それを お前は…
You weren't just going to
target Gastrea, were you?
狙うのは
ガストレアだけじゃねえんだろ？
フンッ
You intend to threaten other
countries with violence?
暴力で 他国を
脅そうというのですか？
Seitenshi-sama, you lack vision.
（斉武）聖天子様
あなたには ビジョンがない
We have to consider what will happen
我々は ガストレアを
駆逐したあとのことまで
after we exterminate the Gastrea.
考えねばならんのだよ
The country that recovers from
that unprecedented disaster first
あの未曽有の災害から
いち早く回復した国こそが
will become the leader of the new world.
新たな世界のリーダーとなる
That is what I'm after.
俺は それを目指している
All those who get in my way will be eliminated.
邪魔立てするものは
全て排除する
Stop fooling around.
ざけんじゃねえよ
I am not fooling around.
ふざけてなどおらぬ
I will have anyone with
power take part in my plan.
力あるものは
全て俺のもとに参画させる
My will is the will of Japan.
俺の意志は 日の本の意志！
The will of Japan, in other words, is my will.
日の本の意志とは すなわち―
俺の意志よ
（聖天子）あ…
Don't be so depressed.
（蓮太郎）そんなに落ち込むなよ
Even Kikunojo had problems handling Saitake.
斉武は 菊之丞でも
手を焼くようなヤツだ
You did well just by not
agreeing to everything he said.
言いなりにならなかっただけでも
あんたは よくやったよ
And you didn't yield to him, either.
あなたこそ
彼を向こうに
一歩も引きませんでしたから
There's no one around me who says
what's on their mind like you do,
あなたみたいに
ハッキリものを言う人は―
周りにいないので
とても 新鮮に映ります
so it was refreshing.
So that's why you chose me?
ああ それで
俺を名指しして依頼を…
It is said that President Saitake
is getting money
（聖天子）斉武大統領は―
and weapons from other countries.
諸外国から
資金や武器などの供与を―
受けていると言われています
What's in it for them?
（蓮太郎）
ヤツらのメリットは なんだ？
Varanium.
（聖天子）バラニウム
As an archipelago of volcanic islands,
火山列島である日本では
バラニウムが豊富に産出される
Japan produces Varanium in abundance.
I'm assuming that, in exchange for Varanium,
あの人は バラニウムの供給と
引き換えに外国の力を借り
he is getting aid from other countries
to help him take over all
five Areas of Japan.
５つに分断された
日本の全てのエリアを
掌握するつもりなのでしょう
Satomi-san, countries from
all over the world will be
里見さん
これから 世界中の国が
日本の各エリアに
contacting the various Areas
of Japan in the future.
様々なコンタクトを
取ってくるでしょう
There will be powerful,
high-ranking civil officers
強力な序列の民警を
送り込んでの暗殺や
sent in for assassinations and sabotage.
破壊工作も行われるはずです
What are you trying to say?
何が言いたいんだ？
The Tokyo Area does not currently have
（聖天子）今の東京エリアには―
the leeway to let efficient
people just fool around.
有能な人材を
遊ばせておく余裕はありません
I will have you working for me continuously.
あなたには これからも
継続的に働いてもらいます
That's rather selfish.
勝手な話だな
I am aware that it is selfish.
勝手は承知しています
I intend to reclaim this
land from the Gastrea,
私は ガストレアから
この地を取り戻し
and connect all of the Areas of Japan.
日本の全てのエリアを
直結させるつもりです
And that is when the
citizens will remember...
そして そのとき
国民は思い出すでしょう
that once, we were all brethren,
gazing up at the same sky.
かつて 我々は
同じ空を見上げていた
同胞であったことを
Even if I'm threatened with
assassination or murder attempts,
私は 暗殺や謀殺が
降りかかろうとも
I will not yield.
決して膝を屈しません
I must embody peace,
私は 平和を
体現しなければならないのです
not with words, but with actions.
言葉ではなく 行動によって！
You're the type of idealist that dies young.
早死にするタイプの理想主義者だ
I don't want to be a person who
can't even speak her ideals.
理想も語れない人間に
なりたくはないのです！
Then conduct yourself better.
（蓮太郎）なら もっと
うまく立ち回れよ
You're an idiot...
though I don't dislike you.
バカだな あんた
嫌いじゃねえけど
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
（蓮太郎）うっ
（聖天子）あ…
It's no use with Rentaro.
蓮太郎はダメだぞ
I'm sorry?
Rentaro has a thing for big boobs,
（聖天子）は？
蓮太郎は おっぱい星人だから
so if your boobs are smaller than Kisara's,
木更より おっぱいが小さいと
女だと認識されないぞ
he won't acknowledge you as a woman.
あ… 不潔です
That's disgusting...
Seriously, what are you saying
right after you wake up?
お前な 起き抜けに何を…
Rentaro.
What?
（延珠）蓮太郎
（蓮太郎）なんだよ
I have a bad feeling...
（延珠）イヤな感じがする
（聖天子･蓮太郎）ん？
（蓮太郎）うっ
（銃声）
（護衛官）うわっ
Get up! Hurry!
（蓮太郎）立て 早く！
Crap!
マズい！
（延珠）はーっ！
Seitenshi-sama! Are you all right?!
聖天子様！ ご無事ですか？
Get her to the cover of the buildings!
建物の陰にお連れしろ！
（虫の羽音のような音）
Rentaro, we must hide quickly!
（延珠）蓮太郎 早く隠れないと！
No, it's fine.
いや 大丈夫だ
The enemy's already gone.
敵は もう引いた
Who the hell are you?
てめえは 誰だ
I'm sorry, Master.
（ティナ）
すみません マスター 失敗です
I have failed.
There was someone rather
skilled among her bodyguards.
護衛に手だれの民警がいました
I shall retrieve the Shenfield and retreat.
シェンフィールドを回収し
撤退します
Did you see any civil officers?
（マスター）民警の姿は見たか？
Yes. However, he was too far away,
so I couldn't make out his face.
はい　しかし 遠すぎて
顔だちまでは見えませんでした
I see...
（マスター）そうか
The one who got in my way...
Just who are you?
私を邪魔した あなたは…
誰？
♪～
～♪
#06 Tragic Irony
This is the first time anyone's
been so nice to me...
（ティナ）
私 こんなに優しくされたの―
I will get that sniper!
生まれて初めて…
I didn't agree to be your bodyguard
just to let you get killed!
生まれて初めて…
（延珠）妾が
あの狙撃手を追う！
（蓮太郎）あんたを
みすみす殺させるために―
護衛を引き受けたわけじゃない！